The Ultimate Dare is to tell the Truth.
Madonna: Truth or Dare is a music, documentary film directed by Alek Keshishian.
From the rains of Japan, through threats of arrest for 'public indecency' in Canada, and a birthday tribute to
her father in Detroit, this documentary follows Madonna on her 1990 'Blond Ambition' concert tour.
Filmed in black and white, with the concert pieces in glittering MTV color, it is an intimate look at the work of
the icon, from a prayer circle before each performance to bed games with the dance troupe afterwards.
Self, played by Madonna.
Self, played by Donna DeLory.
Self, played by Niki Haris.
Self, played by Warren Beatty.
Self, played by Sandra Bernhard.
Self, played by Jean-Paul Gaultier.
Madonna: Truth or Dare (also known as In Bed with Madonna internationally) is a 1991 American documentary film by
director Alek Keshishian chronicling the life of entertainer Madonna during her 1990 Blond Ambition World Tour.
Madonna approached Keshishian to do an HBO special on the
tour after watching his Harvard senior project.
Initially planned to be a traditional concert film, Keshishian was so impressed with the
backstage life that he persuaded Madonna to make it the focus of the film.
Madonna funded the project and served as executive producer.
The film was edited to be in black-and-white, in order to emulate
cinéma vérité, while the performance scenes are in color.
Madonna: Truth or Dare was screened out of competition at the 1991 Cannes Film Festival and was
given a limited release on May 10, 1991; two weeks later, it had its worldwide release.
It opened to positive reviews although certain scenes, such as one
where Madonna visits her mother's grave, were criticized.
Madonna was nominated for a Razzie Award for Worst Actress.
With a worldwide gross of $29 million, it was the highest-grossing documentary
of all time, until Bowling for Columbine surpassed it in 2002.
Truth or Dare has been noted as a groundbreaking film for its casual portrayal
of homosexuality, and was compared to Paris Is Burning (1990).
It has also had an impact on reality television and celebrity culture,
inspiring parodies and other music-related documentaries.
The film explores themes of dance, concert, pop star, eroticism, musical.